APOORVE MOHAN

370 WVH CCIS, 440 Huntington Avenue, Boston, MA 02115, USA

Website: https://www.apoorve.com E-Mail: mohan.ap@husky.neu.edu

SUMMARY

Current research focuses on *improving bare-metal resource efficiency*, which includes the following projects: (a) enabling rapid and secure time-multiplexing of bare-metal servers across co-located clusters to improve aggregate resource efficiency in centralized data centers; (b) non-intrusive software introspection strategy for bare-metal clusters; (c) node-level job co-location strategy that leverages user-space application-transparent checkpoint-restart mechanism to improve throughput in batch clusters.

EDUCATION

Northeastern University

- Ph.D. Computer Engineering (GPA: 3.92/4.00)

2014 - Present

- Thesis Advisor(s): Prof. Gene Cooperman, Prof. Orran Krieger

University of Delhi

- M.Sc. Computer Science

2009 - 2011

- B.Sc. (Hons.) Computer Science

2006 - 2009

SELECTED PUBLICATIONS

Towards Non-intrusive Software Introspection and Beyond, A.Mohan, S.Nadgowda, B.Pipaliya, S.Varma, S.Suneja, C.Isci, G.Cooperman, P.Desnoyers, O.Krieger, A.Turk

(IEEE IC2E 2020)

Supporting Security Sensitive Tenants in a Bare-Metal Cloud, A.Mossayebzadeh, **A.Mohan**, S.Tikale, M.Abdi, N.Schear, T.Hudson, C.Munson, L.Rudolph, G.Cooperman, P.Desnoyers, O.Krieger (USENIX ATC 2019) (Co-first Author)

M2: Malleable Metal as a Service, A.Mohan, A.Turk, R.S.Gudimetla, S.Tikale, J.Hennessey, G.Cooperman, P.Desnoyers, O.Krieger (IEEE IC2E 2018)

RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

Summer Research Intern

2017, 2018

IBM Research T.J. Watson, Yorktown Heights

Mentor: Dr. Gheorghe Almasi

- Projects: Dynamic partitioning of data centers at the bare-metal layer, Analyzing system bottlenecks for distributed DNN training in commodity data centers.

Research Student 2015 - Present

Massachusetts Open Cloud, Boston

Advisor: Prof. Orran Krieger

- Projects: Elastic secure infrastructure, Non-intrusive bare-metal introspection, Bare-metal resource utilization control system.

Graduate Research Assistant

2014 - Present

 $Khoury\ College\ of\ Computer\ Sciences,\ Northeastern\ University,\ Boston$

Advisor: Prof. Gene Cooperman

- Project: Efficient batch processing using user-space checkpoint-restart.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

Project Mentor (Spring)

2018

 $Khoury\ College\ of\ Computer\ Science,\ Northeastern\ University,\ Boston$

- CS 6620 Cloud Computing (Graduate)

Teaching Assistant (Fall)

2016

Khoury College of Computer Science, Northeastern University, Boston

- CS 5600 Computer Systems (Graduate)
- CS 3650 Computer Systems (Undergraduate)

Project Associate 2012 - 2014

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

- Involved in design and implementation of an academic IaaS cloud platform (https://baadal.nmeict.in).

Guest Lecturer Spring, Fall 2013

Maharaja Agrasen College, University of Delhi

- Introduction to Programming, Introduction to Computer Fundamentals (Undergraduate)

Assistant Professor (Adhoc)

Fall 2012

Maharaja Agrasen College, University of Delhi

- Introduction to Programming, Introduction to Computer Fundamentals (Undergraduate)

Software Developer

2011 - 2012

One 97 Communications Ltd., NOIDA

- Developed a parallel batch processing service for provisioning cellular phone numbers to a *Do-Not-Disturb* list for offered value-added services (both backend and frontend).

PRESENTATIONS

Using Elastic Secure Infrastructure in Centralized Environments	(Open Cloud Workshop 2020)
Agentless Bare-Metal Introspection	(Mass Open Cloud Workshop 2018)
Marrying Cloud and HPC for Long-Term Happiness	(IBM Research Workshop 2017)
Elastic OpenStack Deployments	$(OpenStack\ Summit-Boston\ 2017)$
Bare Metal Imaging	(Mass Open Cloud Workshop 2016)

POSTERS

Recycling Lost CPU Cycles

(New England Network and Systems Day 2017)

Marrying Cloud and HPC for Long-Term Happiness

(Supercomputing Conference 2016)